<resources>
    <string name="app_name">StoryProject</string>
    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->

    <string name="Heading">The  Lion and the Man</string>
    <string name="content"> A Lion and a Man chanced to travel in a company through the forest.They soon began to quarrel, for each of them boasted that he and his kind were far superior to the other both in strength and mind.

Now they reached a clearing in the forest and there stood a statue. It was a representation of Heracles in the act of tearing the jaws of the Nemean Lion.


“See,” said the man, “that’s how strong we are! The King of Beasts is like wax in our hands!”



“Ho!” laughed the Lion, “a Man made that statue. It would have been quite a different scene had a Lion made it!”



        Moral: It all depends on the point of view, and who tells the story. Always trust your own wit and try judge the circumstances.
        </string>
    <string name="pig">The Pig and the Sheep</string>
    <string name="pigcontent">
        One day a shepherd discovered a fat Pig in the meadow where his Sheep were pastured. He very quickly captured the porker, which squealed at the top of its voice the moment the Shepherd laid his hands on it. You would have thought, to hear the loud squealing, that the Pig was being cruelly hurt. But in spite of its squeals and struggles to escape, the Shepherd tucked his prize under his arm and started off to the butcher’s in the marketplace.

The Sheep in the pasture were much astonished and amused at the Pig’s behavior and followed the Shepherd and his charge to the pasture gate.

“What makes you squeal like that?” asked one of the Sheep. “The Shepherd often catches and carries off one of us. But we should feel very much ashamed to make such a terrible fuss about it like you do.”



“That is all very well,” replied the Pig, with a squeal and a frantic kick. “When he catches you he is only after your wool. But he wants my bacon! gree-ee-ee!”

Moral: It is easy to be brave when there is no danger. Don’t compare two different situations without understanding them.</string>
    <string name="wolf">The sheperd and the wolf</string>
    <string name="wolfcontent"> A Shepherd Boy tended his master’s Sheep near a dark forest not far from the village. Soon he found life in the pasture very dull. All he could do to amuse himself was to talk to his dog or play on his shepherd’s pipe.

One day as he sat watching the Sheep and the quiet forest, and thinking what he would do should he see a Wolf, he thought of a plan to amuse himself. His Master had told him to call for help should a Wolf attack the flock, and the Villagers would drive it away. So now, though he had not seen anything that even looked like a Wolf, he ran toward the village shouting at the top of his voice, “Wolf! Wolf!”

As he expected, the Villagers who heard the cry dropped their work and ran in great excitement to the pasture. But when they got there they found the Boy doubled up with laughter at the trick he had played on them. A few days later the Shepherd Boy again shouted, “Wolf! Wolf!” Again the Villagers ran to help him, only to be laughed at again.



Then one evening as the sun was setting behind the forest and the shadows were creeping out over the pasture, a Wolf really did spring from the underbrush and fall upon the Sheep.

In terror the Boy ran toward the village shouting “Wolf! Wolf!” But though the Villagers heard the cry, they did not run to help him as they had before. “He cannot fool us again,” they said.

The Wolf killed a great many of the Boy’s sheep and then slipped away into the forest.

Moral: If you keep lying, no one will believe you even if you are speaking the truth. Always speak the truth</string>
    <string name="crane">The Wolf and the crane</string>
    <string name="cranecontent"> A Wolf had been feasting too greedily, and a bone had stuck crosswise in his throat. He could get it neither up nor down, and of course, he could not eat a thing. Naturally, that was an awful state of affairs for a greedy Wolf.

So away he hurried to the Crane. He was sure that she, with her long neck and bill, would easily be able to reach the bone and pull it out. “I will reward you very handsomely”, said the Wolf, “if you pull that bone out for me”.

The Crane, as you can imagine, was very uneasy about putting her head in Wolf’s throat. But she was grasping in nature, so she did what the Wolf asked her to do. When the Wolf felt that the bone was gone, he started to walk away.



“But what about my reward!” called the Crane anxiously.

“What!” snarled the Wolf, whirling around. “Haven’t you got it? Isn’t it enough that I let you take your head out of my mouth without snapping it off?”

Moral: Expect no reward for serving the one who has no honor. Staying in a company of selfish people will not do anyone any favor.</string>
    <string name="wealth">Wealth without Value</string>
    <string name="wealthcontent">A Miser had buried his gold in a secret place in his garden. Every day he went to the spot, dug up the treasure and counted it piece by piece to make sure it was all there. He made so many trips that a Thief, who had been observing him, guessed what it was the Miser had hidden, and one night quietly dug up the treasure and made off with it.

When the Miser discovered his loss, he was overcome with grief and despair. He groaned and cried and tore his hair. A passerby heard his cries and asked what had happened.

“My gold! O my gold!” cried the Miser, wildly, “someone has robbed me!”



“Your gold! There in that hole? Why did you put it there? Why did you not keep it in the house where you could easily get it when you had to buy things?”

“Buy!” screamed the Miser angrily. “Why, I never touched the gold. I couldn’t think of spending any of it.”

The stranger picked up a large stone and threw it into the hole. “If that is the case,” he said, “cover up that stone. It is worth just as much to you as the treasure you lost!”

Moral: Saving, Spending wisely and appropriately is a good sign if you do it for a good purpose. Otherwise, a possession is worth no more than the use we make of it.</string>
    <string name="sun">Why the sun and the moon</string>
    <string name="suncontent">Many years ago, the sun and water were great friends, and they both lived on the earth togther. The sun very often used to visit the water, but the water never returned the visits.

At last the sun asked the water why he never visited. The water replied that the suns house was not big enough, and that if he came with all his people, he would drive the sun out of his home.

The water then said, If you want me to visit you, you will have to build a very large house. But I warn you that it will have to be very large, as my people are numerous and take up a lot of room.

The sun promised to build a very large house, and soon afterwards, he returned home to his wife, the moon, who greeted him with a broad smile.

The sun told the moon what he had promised the water, and the next day, they began building a large house to entertain the water and all his people.

When it was completed, the sun asked the water to come and visit him.

When the water arrived, one of his people called out to the sun, and asked him whether it would be safe for the water to enter, and the sun answered, Yes, tell my friend to come in.

The water began to flow in, followed by the fish and all the other water animals.

Very soon, the water was knee-deep in the house, so he asked the sun if it was still safe, and the sun again said, Yes, so more of them came in.

When the water was at the level of a mans head, the water said to the sun, Do you want more of my people to come

Not knowing any better, the sun and the moon both said, Yes,. More and more of the waters people came in, until the sun and the moon had to sit on top of the roof.

The water once again asked the sun if it was still okay to keep coming in. The sun and moon answered yes, so more and more of the waters people came in.

The water soon overflowed the top of the roof, and the sun and the moon were forced to go up into the sky.

‌…and they have been there ever since.
    </string>
    <string name="friend">The Two Friends</string>
    <string name="friendcontent">One upon a time there were two friends from childhood days named Harry and Peter. Both trusted each other and used to help each other whenever they needed. They grew up together and entered in their respective career. Out of them Harry was quite happy with his small earning but Peter was very greedy and always used to think how to make more wealth and was not happy with small earnings but it did not affect true friendship between them.

Peter came across with one elderly person Jack who told him that he can help him to earn more money, provided he follows him in his way of work. Peter agreed to do whatever Jack wanted him to do. Jack was a criminal and he ultimately involved Peter with him for cheating person through their ATM withdrawal by doing skimming activity. Gradually Peter could earn lots of money and become a rich person.

His childhood friend Harry could realize that Peter must be doing some unlawful job for earning money and become a rich person. Understanding this he started avoiding Peter and ultimately a distance between the two friends happened. Peter earned lots of money and started his own number of business to become wealthier person. About 10 years have passed the two friends were detached from themselves but no body forgets each other from their heart. Suddenly Peter needed a trusted person to look after his business and help him in earning more money. He remembers his old friend Harry and started searching him and his whereabouts. After a long search he came to know that Harry is very much sick and hospitalized and needs lots of money for his surgery. Peter knew that if he gives money to Harry he will not take it. As he has earned the money in dishonest way. But still he wanted to help him and pay all the hospital charges amounting six lakhs with the pretext that the money has come from a charity fund. When Harry recovered from his illness and inquired how the money has come he understands that it is his childhood friend Peter who arranged the money. Harry became angry and met Peter and asked him why he paid his money. Peter simply replied “A friend in need is a friend indeed”.</string>
    <string name="miser">The King and The Beggar</string>
    <string name="misercontent">

Once upon a time a country was ruled by a king who had no son to succeed to the throne.

Since the king was getting old he wanted to select a suitable successor to rule the country.

The king sent out notices throughout his country.

The notice has invited every qualified young man in the country for an interview with the king.

The outcome of the interview would decide a possible successor to the throne.

The only qualification for the candidate was that they should have immense love for their fellow human beings.

Every young man across the country was very excited at the possibility of being the ruler of the country.

A poor young man from a remote Village also read the notice and started to prepare for an interview with the king.

The man was a kind and hard-working man but he was very poor due to various circumstances.

The man had no good clothes to be presentable in the sight of the king.

So the young man worked really hard and saved some money to buy him proper clothes and supplies to support him for the long journey to the palace.

After he got his supplies and a proper attire for the interview the young man set out on his quest.

He traveled many days and had almost completed the journey.

When he came upon a poor beggar by the side of the road, the poor beggar said trembling in the cold covered only in tattered rags.

The beggar extended his arms and pleaded for help.

His weak voice croaked “I am hungry and cold please help me sir”.

The young man was so moved by the pathetic condition of the beggar that he immediately stripped his new attire and offered it to him.

He also provided him with his very limited food he had carried for the journey.

The beggar thanked the man a thousand times but since the man had given up his good clothes to the beggar, he was a bit hesitant to go for the interview.

He however gathered enough courage to enter the palace in his old-dirty clothes.

Upon his arrival at the palace, the King’s attendant showed him the way to the Great Hall.

After a short rest to clean off the journey’s tiredness.

The man was admitted to the throne room for the interview.

The young man bowed low as the King entered the room. when he raised his eyes he gasped in astonishment as he noticed that the King looked very similar to the beggar he had met on the way.

The King saw the shock in the man’s eye and said “yes, I was the beggar you met on your way”

But why did you dress up like a beggar, you are a king!. well, why did you do this to me

The young man stammered after gaining some composure.

“Because, I had to be sure that you had a good heart and you genuinely loved your fellow human beings.” said the king.

I knew that if I came to you as a king you would have done anything to impress me but that way I would never have known what is truly in your heart.

The generosity and love to the one in need without expecting anything in return is the sign of a great heart.

Looking at your love and generosity towards the beggar man proved that you sincerely love your fellow human beings.

This country needs a leader who would work for the welfare of all of the nation not just the ones who would do anything to get the throne.

“You have proven that you are the right person to be my successor” promised the king.

Moral Of The Story:
You see in life kindness is more important than wisdom and the recognition of this is the beginning of wisdom.

A heart filled with compassion and love to our fellow human beings is the greatest gift we can give to the world.

A king in this land today might be rich and glamorous, might have the power and all the strength.

But this kingdom is worthless compared to a rich
heart of the young man.

The kindness and compassion of the young man towards the beggar made him the king of the entire nation.

We, As a human should help other fellow beings in need without expecting anything in return. </string>
    <string name="four">The Four Dragons</string>
    <string name="fourcontent">“The Four Dragons” is a tale from China where long ago, the story says, there were no lakes or rivers, only the Eastern Sea, home to four dragons: the Long Dragon, the Yellow Dragon, the Black Dragon, and the Pearl Dragon. These dragons swam in the sea and flew in the air above. One day, as they were playing in the clouds, the Pearl Dragon saw a disturbing sight he shared with the others. He saw the people down below praying for rain. The land was in a drought, the plants were withering, and the people had nothing to eat. The dragons realized that the people would die if it did not rain soon, so the Long Dragon suggested they visit the Jade Emperor, who was in charge of all the affairs in heaven and earth, and beg for rain. After they made their request the Jade Emperor agreed to send rain.

The dragons happily went back to their home, but the rain never came. After ten days, the dragons realized that the Jade Emperor didn’t truly care about the people and that it was up to them to provide rain. The Long Dragon came up with the idea of scooping water out of the Eastern Sea and spraying it towards the sky, where it would fall on the earth like rain. All the dragons agreed and followed through with the plan, even knowing that the Jade Emperor would be displeased when he found out.

The people were overjoyed when the rain fell, but the god of the sea reported the dragons’ behavior to the Jade Emperor who was furious. He had the four dragons arrested and imprisoned under four mountains. “The Dragons never regretted their decision and determined to continue to do good for the people, they turned themselves into four rivers, which flowed past the high mountains and deep valleys, crossing the land from the west to the east, and finally emptied into the sea. Thus they became China’s four great rivers-the Heilongjian (Black Dragon), the Huanghe (Yellow Dragon), the Changjiang (Long Dragon), and the Zhujiang (Pearl Dragon). ”

You can read the story on-line in several places, including here.

I especially enjoy creation myths, stories that helped people make sense of the world. In this story we have four higher beings giving up their freedom for the lives of the people. I don’t know much about Chinese culture, but dragons seem to be powerful, wise, strong. They are revered, not creatures to be slain as in European stories.

I have to admire the dragons. They saw a problem, saw how desperate the villagers were and became determined to help. They went through the official channels first, making their request to the Jade Emperor, but when that didn’t accomplish anything, they took matters into their own hands. People in charge are not always right, do not always have others’ best interests at heart. The dragons knew they were risking punishment, but they all agreed that it was worth the price and did what needed to be done. Even when they were imprisoned forever, they never regretted their decision and continued to do whatever they could to help the people.

</string>
    <string name="man">The man who never lied</string>
    <string name="mancontent">Once upon a time there lived a wise man by the name of Mamad. He never lied. All the people in the land, even the ones who lived twenty days away, knew about him.

The king heard about Mamad and ordered his subjects to bring him to the palace. He looked at the wise man and asked:

" Mamad, is it true, that you have never lied?"

" It's true."

"And you will never lie in your life?"

" I'm sure in that."

"Okay, tell the truth, but be careful! The lie is cunning and it gets on your tongue easily."

Several days passed and the king called Mamad once again. There was a big crowd: the king was about to go hunting. The king held his horse by the mane, his left foot was already on the stirrup. He ordered Mamad:

"Go to my summer palace and tell the queen I will be with her for lunch. Tell her to prepare a big feast. You will have lunch with me then."

Mamad bowed down and went to the queen. Then the king laughed and said:

"We won't go hunting and now Mamad will lie to the queen. Tomorrow we will laugh on his behalf."

But the wise Mamad went to the palace and said:

"Maybe you should prepare a big feast for lunch tomorrow, and maybe you shouldn't. Maybe the king will come by noon, and maybe he won't."

"Tell me will he come, or won't he?" - asked the queen.

"I don't know weather he put his right foot on the stirrup, or he put his left foot on the ground after I left."

Everybody waited for the king. He came the next day and said to the queen:

"The wise Mamad, who never lies, lied to you yesterday."

But the queen told him about the words of Mamad. And the king realized, that the wise man never lies, and says only that, which he saw with his own eyes.</string>
    <string name="cindrela">Cinderella</string>
    <string name="cindrelacontent">ONCE UPON A TIME a girl named Cinderella lived with her stepmother and two stepsisters.  Poor Cinderella had to work hard all day long so the others could rest. It was she who had to wake up each morning when it was still dark and cold to start the fire.  It was she who cooked the meals. It was she who kept the fire going. The poor girl could not stay clean, from all the ashes and cinders by the fire.

 Cinderella Story
Thank you, Artist Carla Oly



“What a mess!” her two stepsisters laughed.  And that is why they called her “Cinderella.”

One day, big news came to town.  The King and Queen were going to have a ball!  It was time for the Prince to find a bride. All of the young ladies in the land were invited to come.  They were wild with joy! They would wear their most beautiful gown and fix their hair extra nice. Maybe the prince would like them!

At Cinderella’s house, she now had extra work to do.  She had to make two brand-new gowns for her step-sisters.

“Faster!” shouted one step-sister.

“You call that a dress?” screamed the other.

“Oh, dear!” said Cinderella.  “When can I–“

The stepmother marched into the room.  “When can you WHAT?”

“Well,” said the girl, “when will I have time to make my own dress for the ball?”

“You?” yelled the stepmother.  “Who said YOU were going to the ball?”

“What a laugh!” said one step-sister.

“Such a mess!” They pointed at Cinderella.  All of them laughed.

Cinderella said to herself, “When they look at me, maybe they see a mess.  But I am not that way.  And if I could, I WOULD go to the ball.”

Soon the time came for the stepmother and step-sisters to leave for the big party.

 Cinderella Story
Thank you, Artist Carla Oly

Their fine carriage came to the door. The stepmother and step-sisters hopped inside.  And they were off.

“Good-bye!” called Cinderella.  “Have a good time!” But her stepmother and step-sisters did not turn around to see her.

“Ah, me!” said Cinderella sadly.  The carriage rode down the street.  She said aloud, “I wish I could go to the ball, too!”

Then - Poof!

All of a sudden, in front of her was a fairy.

“You called?” said the fairy.

“Did I?” said Cinderella.  “Who are you?”

“Why, your Fairy Godmother, of course!  I know your wish.  And I have come to grant it.”

“But…” said Cinderella, “my wish is impossible.”

“Excuse me!” said the Fairy Godmother in a huff.  “Did I not just show up out of thin air?”

“Yes, you did,” said Cinderella.

“Then let me be the one to say what is possible or not!”

“Well, I think you know I want to go to the ball, too.” She looked down at her dirty clothes.

 “But look at me.”

“You do look a bit of a mess, child,” said the Fairy Godmother.

“Even if I had something nice to wear," said the girl, "I would have no way to get there."

“Dear me, all of that is possible,” said the Fairy. With that, she tapped her wand on Cinderella’s head.

</string>
    <string name="hansel">Hansel and Gretel</string>
    <string name="hanselcontent">A poor woodcutter and his wife had two children named Hansel and Gretel. Their mother died when they were young. Hansel and Gretel were very sad. Soon their father remarried but their stepmother was very cruel. One day, she took the children deep into the forest and left them there. Clever Hansel had some breadcrumbs in his pocket and had dropped them on the way so that they could find their way back home. Alas! The birds ate all the crumbs and they couldn’t find the path that led back home.

Hansel and Gretel went deeper and deeper into the forest. They were hungry and tired. Finally, after walking for a long time, they saw a cottage made of chocolate, candies, and cake. “Look, Hansel! A chocolate brick!” shouted

Gretel in delight and both ate it hungrily.
        Now, a wicked witch lived there. When she saw Hansel and Gretel, she wanted to eat them. She grabbed the children and locked them in a cage. The witch decided to make a soup out of Hansel and eat him first. She began boiling a huge pot of water for the soup. Just then, Gretel crept out of her cage. She gave the wicked witch a mighty push from behind and the witch fell into the boiling water. She howled in pain and died instantly. Hansel and Gretel found treasure lying around the cottage. They carried it home with them. Their stepmother had died and their father welcomed them back with tears of joy. They never went hungry again!
    </string>
    <string name="ugly">The Ugly Duckling</string>
    <string name="uglycontent">On a farm long ago, a Mama Duck sat on her nest.  “How long must I wait for my babies to hatch?” she said.  “I have to sit here all alone! And no one comes to visit me.”  But what could she do? A Mama duck must keep her eggs warm till they hatch.

At last, the eggs began to crack.  One by one, yellow ducklings stepped out of their shells.  They shook their wings and said, “Quack, quack!”

“Look at all of you!” said Mama Duck with joy.  “You are all so cute!”

“Quack, quack!” they said.

Mama Duck said, “Come and line up.  We will go down to the lake for your very first swim.”  She counted – one, two, three, four, five. “Oh dear!” she said.  “I should have six ducklings!”

But one large egg was still in the nest. “Well," said Mama Duck, "it looks like that big egg will take more time.” So she had to go sit on her nest again and wait some more.

The next day, the big egg started to hatch.  Out came a baby boy bird. But if one may say so, it was an odd-looking thing.  This bird was much bigger than others. He was not yellow at all - he was dark-gray from his head to his feet.  And he walked with a funny wobble.






One of the yellow ducklings pointed.  “What is THAT? He cannot be one of us!”

“I have never seen such an ugly duckling!” said another.

“How can you say such a thing?” said Mama Duck in a stern voice. “You are only one day old!  Your brother hatched from the very same nest as you did. Now line up. We will go to the lake for your very first swim.”

Yet the other ducklings quacked, “Ugly!  Ugly! Ugly!” The Ugly Duckling did not know why the other ducklings were yelling at him.  He took the last spot in the line.

Each yellow duck jumped in the river and swam behind Mama Duck.  When it was his turn, the Ugly Duckling jumped in and started to paddle, too.  “At least he can swim,” Mama Duck said to herself.

When they left the water and started to play, the Ugly Duckling tried to play with his brothers and sisters, too.  They yelled, “Go away! We will not play with you! You are ugly. And you walk weird, too!”






When Mama Duck was close by, she would not let them talk in this way.  “Be nice!” she would scold. But she was not always close by.

One day, one of the yellow ducklings said to the Ugly Duckling, “You know what?  You would do us a big favor if you just went away from here!” All of them started to quack, “Get out!  Get out! Get out!”

“Why won’t they let me stay here?” said the Ugly Duckling to himself.  He hung his head down low. “Ah, they are right. I should go.”

That night, the Ugly Duckling flew over the farmyard fence.  He flew till he landed on the other side of the lake.  There he met two grown-up ducks.

“Can I please stay here for awhile?” said the Ugly Duckling.  “I have nowhere else to be.”

“What do we care?” said one of the ducks.  “Just don’t get in our way.”


Thanks to Roopkotha,5, Bangladesh



“Woof! Woof!”  Suddenly a big hungry dog came tearing by, chasing the two ducks.  They quickly flew up in the air, and their feathers fell down on the ground.  The poor Ugly Duckling froze in fear. The dog sniffed and sniffed at the Ugly Duckling, then turned away.  “I am too ugly even for the big hungry dog to want,” said the Ugly Duckling with his head hung low.

The sky turned dark.  Crack!  A bolt of lightning.  Then came a big storm, with heavy rains pouring down from the sky.  In just moments, the Ugly Duckling was soaked through and through. Then a cold wind started to blow.

“Brrr!” he said with both wings held close to his chest.  “If only there was a place I could get dry.”

All at once, a tiny light blinked far off in the woods.  “Could it be someone’s hut?”

He flew to the door.  “Quack?” said the Ugly Duckling.  The door of the hut creaked open.

“What is all this noise?” said an old woman, looking right and left.  Her eyes were not that good. Then she looked down. “Ah, look at that, it’s a duck!”  She picked up the Ugly Duckling and dropped him inside her hut. “You can stay here, but only if you lay eggs,” she said.

A tomcat and hen crept up to the Ugly Duckling.  “Who do you think you are, coming in here and taking up room by the fire!” said the tomcat.

“Squawk!” said the hen.  “I do not need anyone else in this hut laying eggs.”

“Do not worry about that,” said the Ugly Duckling.  “I am a boy duck.”

“Then why are you still here?” said the tomcat.  “Did you not hear what the old woman said?”

“Get out of here, pretender!” clucked the hen.

“Get out!  Get out!“ hissed the tomcat.

The door was still a bit open, so our poor Ugly Duckling slipped out the door, and back into the storm.

“No one ever wants me,” said the Ugly Duckling with a tear in his eye.

The storm ended.  Soon he found a new lake.  Looking into the water, the Ugly Duckling saw the reflection of a flock of large white birds flying.  He looked overhead and could not believe what he saw. There, above him, were the most beautiful birds he had ever seen!  Their long white bodies and slender necks seemed to just glide through the sky. He watched until the very last bird had winged its way out of view.






He stayed at that lake all by himself, and time passed.  The leaves of the trees turned deep red and gold, and then the leaves fell to the ground.  Winter came, setting a blanket of white snow all over. The cold wind and the dark clouds made the Ugly Duckling feel even more sad.

He had to go into the cold, cold lake to fish, but it was getting harder to swim.  The lake was turning to ice. One day, it was all he could do was to paddle the water to keep it from freezing around him, and trapping him in the lake.

“I am so tired!” he said, paddling with all his might.  The ice got thicker and drew closer to him.

In a moment, two giant hands swept him up.  “You poor thing!” said a farmer. He held the Ugly Duckling close to his thick wool jacket and took the bird to his home.

Never was a warm fireplace more welcome!  For the rest of the winter, the farmer cared for the Ugly Duckling.  Then spring came. Tips of green covered the trees. Short, bright flowers popped up from the ground.

“It is time for you to go to the lake to swim again, as you were born to do,” said the farmer.  He took the duckling back to the lake where he had found him, and set him with care on the water.

“Gosh, I feel strong,” said the young bird, flapping his wings.  “Why, I never felt as strong as I do right now!”

He heard quiet splashing sounds behind him, and turned around.  A flock of those same beautiful birds he had seen in the sky before landed behind him on the water.

“Do not worry!” he said to them, holding out one wing.  “I will go now. I will not make trouble for you.” A big fat tear rolled down his cheek.  He turned to go away. When he opened his eyes, he saw a reflection in the water of one of those beautiful white birds.  Why was it so close to him? He jumped back. And the reflection jumped back, too.





“What is this?” he said.  He stretched his neck, and the reflection of the beautiful bird stretched its neck, too.

“Why are you going so soon?” said one of the beautiful birds.

“Stay here, with us!” said another.  “We’ll be great friends.”

Then, the bird who used to be the Ugly Duckling knew what had happened!  He was no longer an ugly gray bird that wobbled when it walked.

At one moment, all the swans flapped their wings and took off into the sky. “Come with us,” one called back. “Take the lead!” So he flapped his wings fast and took his place in front of the whole flock.  All his new friends flapped their wings behind him.

“Say!” he said, gliding and dipping through the sky as he sped on.  “Who’s an ugly duckling now? Surely, Not I!</string>
    <string name="bambi">Bambi Story</string>
    <string name="bambicontent">One day a deer was born.  His title was Bambi.  His mom washed him throughout together with her tongue.

“Bambi,” she stated.  “My little Bambi.”

The younger Bambi was interested by the whole lot.  He realized he was a deer, and so was his mom.  He realized there are different deer within the forest, and sometime he would meet them. He realized the paths his mom adopted have been made by the deer. Bugs and critters, sounds and smells. So many wonders to discover!

Typically on a path, immediately his mom would cease nonetheless.  She would open her ears broad and pay attention from all instructions. First- over there! Then- right here!  Bambi would wait.  Eventually, when she stated, “It’s all proper.  There’s no hazard. We are able to go,” then the 2 of them would begin on the path once more.  However he didn’t know why they’d to do that.

Typically on a path, his mom would cease nonetheless.

Sooner or later, his mom took him to the meadow for the primary time.  He began to expire to the open clearing however she jumped proper in entrance of him.  “Cease!” stated she. “Keep right here.  I have to exit first. Wait until I name for you.  But when I begin to run, you need to flip round and run again into the woods very quick.  Don’t cease.  Do you perceive me?”

Bambi’s mom slowly stepped out into the open meadow.  She sniffed throughout.  She regarded this manner and that, alert and punctiliously.  After awhile she stated, “It’s advantageous, Bambi.  Nothing to fret about.  Come on!” He bounded out to fulfill her.

Oh, what a brilliant solar!  Again within the woods, Bambi had seen a stray sunbeam once in a while, however right here the recent brilliant solar warmed him throughout.  He felt marvelous and jumped excessive into the air.  Every time he landed on grass softer than any grass he had ever felt.  Then he leaped again up once more, again and again.

In some locations the flowers have been so thick, they made a candy carpet.   However what was that tiny factor dancing within the air?  “Look, Mom!” stated Bambi.  “The flower is flying.” Why, that flower will need to have wanted to bounce a lot, Bambi thought, that it broke proper off its stem to stand up and dance within the air.

“That’s not a flower, Bambi,” stated the mom, “it’s a butterfly.”

“Look Mom!” stated Bambi.  “The flower is flying.”

Then – Thump, thump, thump!  On a rock was a younger hare, a rabbit, thumping its foot.

“Hey, there!” smiled Hare, elevating one tall ear. “Need to play?”

“Positive!” stated Bambi.

“Catch me!”  Hare hopped off the rock into the grass, hop-hopping away. Bambi was a bit quicker at operating and leaping, however Hare was higher at hiding, so the 2 of them had a advantageous time.

On high of the flowers, a tall, fluffy black and white tail was sliding over to them.  “Why, I’d know that tail wherever!” stated Hare.  “It’s my good friend Skunk.  He’s underneath the flowers.  Skunk?”  And positive sufficient, a black and white head popped up.

“That is Bambi,” stated Hare.  Quickly the three of them have been exploring the meadow, sniffing its wealthy deep smells.

And positive sufficient, a black and white head popped up.

After awhile, Hare and Skunk needed to go dwelling.  Bambi regarded round.  “Mom! The place are you?”  On the far facet of the meadow he noticed her, with a creature that regarded similar to her.

“Bambi, come meet my sister Ena,” known as Bambi’s mom.  “And her two little ones.”  Bambi hopped over.  Two fawns, little Faline and her brother Gobo, have been operating out and in of their mom’s legs.

Faline gave a leap and landed proper in entrance of Bambi, then jumped again to Gobo.  With care, Bambi stepped as much as her.  Faline hopped off to 1 facet and Gobo adopted.  Quickly the three of them have been chasing one another up and down the grass.

“Now run off and play, all of you,” stated Bambi’s mom.

Daily after that, the three younger deer performed and chattered.  They raced and chased, they nibbled many strawberries and blueberries on the bushes, and generally they simply talked.

Daily after that, the three younger deer performed and chattered.

Sooner or later, Bambi stated, “Have you learnt what hazard means?”

“One thing very unhealthy,” whispered Gobo.

“However what’s it?” stated Bambi.

“I do know what hazard is,” stated Faline.  “It’s what you run away from.”  However quickly they have been chasing and taking part in once more.

Bambi’s mom and Ena got here up.  “Come on now,” they stated. “It’s time to go dwelling.”

Far off on the high of a hill two giant proud deer got here into view, with huge heads of antlers.

Turning to them, Faline stated, “Who’re they?”

“These are your fathers,” stated Ena.

“In case you are sensible and don’t run into hazard,” stated Bambi’s mom to her son, “sometime you’ll develop up as huge and good-looking as your father. And you’ll have antlers, too.”  Bambi’s coronary heart swelled with delight.

“These are your fathers,” stated Ena.

As Bambi grew, he realized the right way to sniff the air.  He might inform if his good friend Hare was coming, or if a fox had simply trotted by.  He might inform if it might rain quickly.

One afternoon got here a raging storm.  Lightning flashed and thunder crashed.  Bambi thought the top of the world had come.  However when he lay by his mom’s facet, he felt secure.

Sooner or later when Bambi wandered about within the woods, he came across a pointy, disagreeable odor.  Curious, he adopted it.  It led to a clearing, the place stood an odd creature.  He had by no means seen such a creature.  It stood up on its rear legs, and in its two arms it held one thing lengthy and black – might it’s a 3rd leg?  The odor of the creature by some means crammed him with terror. The creature raised its lengthy black arm.  In a flash, Bambi’s mom rushed as much as him.

“Run, Bambi, run!  As quick as you may!”

In a flash, Bambi’s mom rushed as much as him.

Bambi’s mom bounded over shrubs and bushes.  He stored tempo beside her until they have been again at their leafy dwelling.

Later, Bambi’s mom stated, “Did you see the Human?”  Bambi nodded sure.  “That’s the one who brings hazard,” she stated.  And each of them shuddered.

Bambi was nonetheless rising.  The primary time he woke to seek out his mom gone from his facet, he was scared.  It was early morning and nonetheless darkish.  “Mom! Mom!” he known as out. A big shadow approached, greater than his mom’s.  Standing earlier than a pool of moonlight, a Nice Outdated Buck regarded proud and stern.

“Who’re you calling?” stated the Buck with a frown.  “Can’t you deal with your self?”  Bambi didn’t dare reply. He lowered his head in disgrace.   “Lookup,” stated the Outdated Buck, “Hearken to me.  Watch.  Odor.  Discover out for your self.  You may be advantageous by yourself.”

Standing earlier than a pool of moonlight, a Nice Outdated Buck regarded proud and stern.

The leaves fell and Bambi grew even taller.  His mom began leaving him alone an increasing number of, letting him meet different deer and creatures of the forest. Faline, Gobo, Hare and Skunk have been nonetheless Bambi’s finest associates, however he additionally discovered different creatures fascinating to look at and generally enjoyable to play with.

One moist winter day, the horrible odor of People swept throughout the forest.  The scent was so sturdy that there needed to be many People in a gaggle! Most animals shortly fled out of hazard.  However some weren’t as fortunate.  With the hunter’s loud noise and nice energy, many animals have been killed and one in all them was Bambi’s mom.

After that horrible day, Bambi felt misplaced.  He wandered about. How might this terrible factor have occurred?  Instantly, the Nice Outdated Buck stepped out in entrance of him.

“Have been you out within the meadow when it occurred?” the Outdated Buck stated.

“Sure,” stated Bambi.

“Have been you out within the meadow when it occurred?” the Outdated Buck stated.

“And also you’re not calling to your mom?” stated the Buck.

Instantly Bambi felt filled with braveness.  “I can deal with myself!” he stated, trying up.

The Nice Outdated Buck smiled.  “Hearken to me,” he stated.  “Odor.  Watch. Be taught to stay and watch out. Discover out for your self.  Now farewell.”  And he vanished into the deep forest.

Winter got here.  Sturdy and bitter chilly winds swept via the woods.  Deep snow coated the forest ground.  There was little meals to eat.  Bambi felt hungry and chilly on a regular basis.  Practically all of the bark on the bushes had been peeled away by hungry deer.  Nonetheless, the chilly wind blistered on, day after day.

Gobo had all the time been smaller than Bambi and Feline.  He shivered on a regular basis.  He might hardly arise anymore.

Sooner or later a flock of crows flew overhead, yelling loudly.  “Caw!  Caw!”  The geese additionally screamed within the sky, “Gawk! Gawk!” They warned of the People coming – once more!

Sooner or later a flock of crows flew overhead, yelling loudly.

Hare hopped up and down in alarm.  “We’re surrounded!  They’re all over the place!” A single growth crashed like thunder, and one goose fell from the sky.  All of the animals ran like mad, even the tiny tit mouse.  One other brief crash like thunder, and a fox fell down on the forest ground.  Bang! Bang!

Hare known as out to Bambi, “We’ve got to get out of right here!”  Bambi and Hare began to sure away.  However was that Gobo, mendacity within the snow?

“Gobo!” stated Bambi. “The place is your mom and Faline?”

“I fell down,” stated Gobo.  “I’m too weak.  You go on, Bambi.”

One other younger deer bounded by.  “Bambi, run!  Don’t simply stand there when you can run!”  He took off just like the wind, and as Bambi ran alongside, he known as behind him, “I’ll come again for you, Gobo!” Bambi ran and ran.  Quickly the sound that boomed as loud as thunder grew an increasing number of distant.

When Bambi returned to the place Gobo had been, there was no hint of him, not even his tracks.  Simply huge tracks.  Faline and her mom have been pacing across the spot.  “What has turn out to be of him?” wailed Ena.  However all of them knew.  They might odor it. A Human had come and had taken Gobo away.

When Bambi returned to the place Gobo had been, there was no hint of him.

Weeks handed. Eventually, little sprigs of contemporary inexperienced grass popped up via the snow.  Then an increasing number of tufts of inexperienced.  What was left of the snow melted away.  On Bambi’s head, he might really feel the load of his fast-growing antlers.

Because the bushes and bushes turned inexperienced and the climate warmed, all of the animals began to behave so oddly.  Birds flitted about two by two.  So many creatures giant and small have been in pairs.  His good friend Skunk spent all his time was with a lady skunk and hardly seen Bambi.  Even his good friend Hare appeared in a daze, endlessly gazing a lady hare and thumping his foot.

“What’s occurred to my associates?” stated Bambi.  “I’m alone.”  There was a rustling within the leaves behind him.  There stood Faline, however she was grown up now, like he was.  Every of them was considering, “How totally different you look!”  They gazed at one another and smiled.

“It’s a very long time since we noticed one another,” stated Faline.

They gazed at one another and smiled.

“Sure, I do know,” stated Bambi.  They talked of outdated instances.  “Do you keep in mind taking part in Tag on the meadow?” stated one.  “Do you keep in mind all of the berries on the bushes we ate?” stated the opposite.  The 2 appeared to know one another completely.

A fats deer got here as much as them, sniffing the air.

“Sister, don’t you realize me?”

Faline and Bambi turned in amazement.  “Gobo!”  They rushed as much as him in pleasure.

“So that you’re not useless!” stated Bambi.

“The place have you ever been?” stated Faline.

Gobo informed his story.  “I used to be with a Human.  I’ve seen much more than the remainder of you, all collectively.” Canines had discovered him when he lay within the snow, and so they barked.  The Human got here and carried Gobo to the place the place he lived.  “It was as heat as summer time inside,” stated Gobo.  “Rain could pour exterior, however not inside the place People stay.  It’s all the time dry and heat!  And there may be all the time one thing to eat, too – turnips, hay, potatoes, carrots – yum!”

Gobo informed his story.  “I used to be with a Human.”

“Weren’t you afraid, although?” stated Faline.

“No, the Human wouldn’t harm me.  If he loves you, or when you serve him, he’s good to you,” stated Gobo.  “All of them cherished me there.  The youngsters petted me.”

The Nice Outdated Buck strode out from the bushes.  “What sort of band is that you’ve in your neck?”

“It’s a halter I put on,” stated Gobo.  “It’s an awesome honor to put on the Human’s halter.”

“Be silent!” stated the Nice Outdated Buck.  “You poor factor.”  He turned and was gone.

Sooner or later when Gobo and Bambi have been collectively, they smelled the scent of a Human.  “We should disguise, directly!” stated Bambi.  “No want for that,” stated Gobo.  “The People know me.” Then all of sudden a pointy bang!  And Gobo fell down.

Thankfully, the Human by no means got here after Gobo.  As a substitute, when the scent of the Human went away, Bambi pulled his good friend to a leafy place the place he might relaxation and be out of hazard.  Bambi knew what weeds his mom used to eat to heal a wound quicker.  As he introduced the weeds to Gobo, he puzzled, “Why should this all the time occur to us?” Bambi considered the Nice Outdated Buck who had stated, “Discover out for your self.” Discover out what?

Faline and Ena introduced Gobo meals and visited with him for hours. Bambi usually got here by, too, till Gobo was healed. The phrases from the Nice Outdated Buck nonetheless contemporary in his head – “Be taught to stay and watch out.” Bambi was beginning to perceive.

Seasons got here and went.  Bambi grew nonetheless taller.  His antlers have been almost full grown now.  Sooner or later, Bambi caught a brand new warning odor within the air.  It was a scorching and smoky odor.  A flock of crows rushed overhead, cawing loudly.  Fireplace!

Without delay, the animals have been operating, operating, as quick as they may.  It wasn’t straightforward to run away from fireplace.  Typically it appeared to hurry in from totally different instructions.  After hours glided by of flames and smoke, the fireplace began to wind down finally.  The odor of fireplace was fading, too.

The Nice Outdated Buck stepped in entrance of Bambi. His head was grey now, however he nonetheless bore his antlers with delight.  “Include me,” he stated in a severe method.  “I need to present you one thing earlier than I am going.”

He led Bambi via the woods to a burned-out village.  Blended together with the odor of fireplace was the identical terrible odor of People that had despatched terror to their hearts repeatedly.

“Include me,” he stated in a severe method.  “I need to present you one thing earlier than I am going.”

“Don’t be frightened,” stated the Outdated Buck.  Nearer and nearer they went to the village.  “Look, Bambi,” stated he.  There in entrance of them have been dozens of huts.  Every one was burned, some virtually to the bottom, others burned totally on the roof.  The village was empty.

“You see, Bambi,” stated the Outdated Buck.  “The homes of the People get burned by fireplace similar to the locations the place we keep within the woods.  The Human isn’t above us.  We’re simply the identical. Do you perceive me, Bambi?”

“Fireplace burns the woods the place we stay, and it burns the villages of People, too,” stated Bambi.  “We aren’t so totally different from People.”

“We each stay underneath the identical nice powers on this world,” stated the Nice Outdated Buck.

“Sure,” stated Bambi.

“Now I can go,” stated the Nice Outdated Buck.  “Don’t comply with me.  My time is up.  Goodbye my son, I cherished you so.”

Now Bambi had turn out to be a full Buck himself.  His antlers spiked and gleamed within the solar.

Typically he would go to the nook of the woods the place he had spent his childhood.  A number of the trails have been nonetheless there.  As soon as whereas wandering there he noticed Gobo and his sister, Faline. When he noticed Faline, his coronary heart beat quicker. He wished to hurry to her.  He gazed after her.  Lastly she was gone.  Then he heard the decision of two little fawns.

As soon as whereas wandering there he noticed Faline, and his coronary heart beat quicker.

“Mom!  Mom!” they known as.

“Can’t you keep by yourselves?” stated Bambi.  The little brother and sister have been an excessive amount of in awe of the nice Buck to reply. Bambi thought, this little fellow pleases me.  He jogs my memory of the deer face I used to see after I regarded within the brook years in the past. Maybe I’ll meet him once more.  The little woman is good, too.  Faline regarded like that when.

“Hearken to me,” stated Bambi to the 2 fawns.  “You need to watch and pay attention. Discover out for your self.  You may be advantageous by yourself.”</string>
    <string name="stone">The Sword in the stone</string>
    <string name="stonecontent">The Sword in the Stone, a King Arthur Legend of the Sword Story ~ Legends Stories for Kids
This is the Tale of The Sword in the Stone, a King Arthur Legend of the Sword Story. It is one of the many tales of King Arthur and the Knights of the Round Table.It is adapted and brought to you by Stories to Grow by.







Long ago in England, a wise and just king ruled the land.  His name was King Uther. Times were good and the people lived well.  King Uther wanted a magician at court. And so he chose the famous Merlin the Magician.  Merlin could see into the future. And he knew those good days were not going to last.

King Uther and the Queen Guinevere had a child, a baby son.  At a castle party for the royal birth, Merlin the Magician took the King aside.  He said, “Sire, there is something you must know. Soon a great darkness will fall over this land.  Your child is in great danger. Let me take the baby far away. I will be sure he stays safe.”

“Merlin!” said the King in surprise. “You are a great magician.  And you are my friend. But there is no way we would let anyone take our child away!”








Sadly, soon after the child’s birth the Queen died.  Not long after, King Uther was killed in battle. That very night, Merlin swept into the castle and took the child.  The next morning, the royal nurse went into the nursery. Alas, an empty crib! In fear, the nurse, the nobles and servants looked everywhere.  But the baby was gone!

For years, there was no king to sit on the throne.  No king to set the laws. Men of high rank fought each other to be king.  Darkness fell over the land. Robbers and bands of wild men ruled the streets of London.  Evil men broke into houses and took what they wanted. Travelers on the roads were jumped and robbed.  The people of England lived in fear.

Yet far away, there was a quiet place.  A good knight, Sir Ector, lived in peace with his two sons.  His first son was named Kay. His younger son Arthur had been adopted as a baby.  Years before, a stranger had come to Sir Ector with a baby. He asked if Sir Ector would raise the child.  The old knight took the baby in his arms, glad for a second child. He named the baby Arthur, and raised the child as his own.






When Arthur was ten years old, the same stranger returned to Sir Ector’s home.  He could read and write, and so Sir Ector hired him to teach his two sons. Kay could not sit still for lessons and he stopped coming.  But Arthur listened with wide eyes. He learned everything. I bet you have guessed by now who that stranger was – none other than Merlin the Magician!

At the end of each day when Arthur finished his chores, that was time for the lessons.  Merlin would sit with Arthur for hours and teach him about the world. Arthur was a thin lad, not strong like his big brother Kay.  Merlin said not to worry about that. He said what mattered most was to have a heart that was big and strong. Merlin saw how the birds, foxes and deer followed Arthur.  He could see that the boy had a very big and strong heart.








By the time Arthur was 16, his brother Kay had become a knight.  He was now called Sir Kay. Arthur loved nothing more than to serve his brother as a squire.  He kept great care of his brother’s tunic and helmet, his spears and lances.

One day at lesson time, Merlin looked away.  He stood up.

“What is it?” said Arthur.

“The people need hope,” said Merlin.  “Arthur, there is something I must do.  I must go now.”

That night, when the nighttime was at its most dark, Merlin the Magician came to London’s market square.  He stood in the middle of the square. He held both his arms high. And pointed his wand to the stars.

The next morning at dawn, people started to arrive at the market.  There in front of them was something most odd. A block of white marble stood in the middle of the town square.  Resting on the block was a giant stone the size of a very large rock. At the very top of the stone there was a golden sword handle and a few inches of the blade, shining in the sun.  Yet – this was most odd – the rest of the blade was buried deep into the stone. None of this was there the day before!

What’s more, these words could be seen on the top of the blade:

“Whoever pulls out this sword from this stone is the true king of England!”






As soon as the crowd knew about the message, men jumped up to that white marble block. One after another, they gave the sword a yank. Each tried and tried, but the sword stuck fast. It would not move.

One said in gloom, “There is no man alive who could pull out that sword!”

“We’ll see about that!” said a voice in the crowd.  The Duke of Cornwall, dressed in silks and ribbons, stepped up to the white marble block.  “Hear ye, hear ye!” he said. “I call for a tournament to be held, one month from today. Knights from anywhere and everywhere in England are invited to come.  There will be contests and prizes. And a grand feast for all!” The Duke said to his wife, the Duchess, “If I know men, this tournament will draw the strongest, finest knights in all of England!”

Said the Duchess, “Good idea, my dear.  All we need is one knight who is so strong he can pull that sword from the stone.  Then we will have a king again, at last!”

The people danced and cheered.  At last there was something to feel happy about! News of the tournament traveled fast.  From castle to village, to every far corner of the land. At last, word got to the far-away home of Sir Ector.  Sir Kay heard the news when he was polishing his helmet.

“Arthur!” he called out.  Arthur was once again by the woods, feeding birds from his hand.  He set down a pile of seeds for the birds, and a pile for the squirrels.  Then he ran fast to see his brother.






“There you are!” said Kay.  “There will be a tournament in London.  We must set out at once!”

What great news! Arthur had never been more than a few miles from home.  He would be the best squire ever for his brother! Arthur ran back to the house.  In the courtyard his father was getting the horses ready.

Sir Ector and his two sons rode through London on their way to the tournament.  Riding through the market square, something shiny glinted in the sun. “That sword looks like it goes right into that stone,” said Arthur.  “But how can that be? That’s impossible.” But why were guards standing all around it?

The father and his two sons reached the tournament. Sir Kay ran off to get in line to register.  Sir Ector greeted many old friends – dukes, earls, barons, counts and countesses. Arthur sat in their tent, polishing his brother’s helmet till it shone bright.

A bugle sounded.  The tournament was about to begin! “Get my sword, demanded Kay”

“Right away,” said Arthur.  But where was it? Arthur looked around in panic.  Kay’s spear, battle-axe, and dagger were right where they should be.  But no sword. “Kay…” he said, “how about a battle-axe?”

“Arthur, I said my sword!”

“Yes, of course,” said Arthur.  “But just a moment.”

“Be quick about it!” said Kay.

Arthur ran back into the tent.  Maybe he had left Kay’s sword there?  He searched through the bag of armor and weapons.  How could he let such a thing happen? Then he had an idea.

Very fast, Arthur rode back to the market square.  The guards were not there anymore – they must have all gone to the tournament.

Arthur stepped up on the marble block.  “Let’s see if that sword can get unstuck.”  He took hold of the handle of the sword. He moved the sword a bit.  “Hey!” he said. “It’s looser than I thought.”






With one big tug, the sword slid out.  Arthur was thrown back, but the sword was safe in his hands.  “I will be sure to bring it right back.” He raced to the where his brother was waiting.

“Here it is,” he said, handing the sword to his brother.

Kay took one look.  “Oh!” he said in surprise.

“What is it?” said Arthur.  But his brother was gone. Soon after, he heard his brother’s voice outside the tent.  “Father, I have something to show you.” Kay and his father stepped inside the tent.

“Look!” said Kay.  He pointed to the sword.

Sir Ector stared.  His face turned white.  “Kay,” said the father, facing his older son, “where did you get this sword?”

“It is mine!” said Kay, holding it close to him.  “I have it now.”

“Kay!” said the Father again in a stern voice.  “I will ask you one more time. Where did you get this sword?”

The young knight’s head dropped down.

“From Arthur,” he said.  “He lost my sword! Somehow he got this one.”

“Arthur?” The father turned to his younger son.  “How is it that you came by this sword?”

“I’m sorry!” said Arthur.  “Father, I will put it back right away.  I only meant to borrow it when I pulled it from the stone.”

“You must take us to where you found this sword.  At once!” The three of them rushed over to the market square.

Arthur climbed up onto the marble block.  “It came from here,” he said. He lifted the sword over his head.






Then he dropped the blade back into the stone. “Now it’s back.”

“Hey,” said Sir Kay.  “I still need a sword!”  He jumped up onto the marble block.  Grabbing the hilt of the sword, he pulled and pulled.  But it did not move.

Kay shouted to Arthur, “What did you do to it?”

“Nothing!” said the lad.

“You must have done something!” yelled Sir Kay.

“Hush! Both of you!” said the father.  “It is better if no one sees or hears us.”

But it was too late.  A crowd had already started to form.

“Hey! Did you pull that sword out of the stone?” called one.

“Yes,” said Arthur. “I did.”

“Do it again!” called another from the crowd.

“Yes, let’s see it!”

Arthur put his hands around the golden handle.  With one tug, the blade slid out.

“Who are you?” called another voice. “What’s your name?”

“Arthur,” said the lad.

“Wait a minute, put that sword back!” A tall knight pushed forward from the crowd.  “Anyone can pull it out, once it’s been pulled!”

“Go ahead.  Put it back, son,” said a voice.  It was the Duke of Cornwall, the one who had called for the tournament.

“All right,” said Arthur. He slipped the blade back into the stone, with ease.

“Let me at that now!” said the tall knight.  He jumped up and grabbed the handle of the sword.  But pull and tug as he might, the sword would not move.  Not even a bit.

Another knight tried.  Then another. But no one could move the sword. Some waited, thinking the longer they pulled the sword, the looser it would get.  But when each man took their turn, the sword did not move for them.

“Let the lad try now,” said the Duke of Cornwall.  “Arthur, go ahead.”

Arthur stepped up to the stone again.  In one motion he freed the sword. This time, he held it high above his head.  The blade flashed in the sun. Amazed, the crowd did not know what to think.

One called out at last.  “He must be our new king!”

“We have a king!” called another. “At last!”

“Stop!” shouted the tall knight.  “Do you really think this skinny boy should rule over all of us?”

“Yes!” said a voice.  All eyes turned around.  It was Merlin the Magician.

“I know this boy. I know his heart.  There is no one in England who has a heart that is bigger and stronger than his.  The sword has told us this young man is to be the next king of England. And there is something else!”







“The lad,” said Merlin, pointing to Arthur, “is the true child of King Uther.  He is the missing baby!”

Cheers began to ring out.  “Hail, King Arthur!” called someone from the crowd.

Sir Ector fell to his knees.  Then Sir Kay. One person after another fell to their knees, too.  All cheered. At last, a king had been chosen. A fresh young king, and a new day for England!   </string>
</resources>